// Quesitons for Harry Potter Category
// One object for each question

const lotrQuestions = [

   {
      "question" : "What was the name of Sauron's fortress in Mordor?",
      "correctAns" : "Barad-D&ucircr",
      "multChoice" : ["Orthanc", "Barad-D&ucircr", "Cirith Ungol", "Dor L&oacutemon"]
   },

   {
      "question" : "Who wrote the poem 'All that is gold does not glitter, Not all those who wander are lost'?",
      "correctAns" : "Bilbo Baggins",
      "multChoice" : ["Thorin Oakenshield", "Arwen Und&oacutemiel", "Bilbo Baggins", "Merry Brandybuck", "L&uacutethien Tin&uacuteviel"]
   },

   {
      "question" : "What is the name of the innkeep at The Prancing Pony?",
      "correctAns" : "Barliman Butterbur",
      "multChoice" : ["Barliman Butterbur", "Tom Bombadil", "Farmer Maggot", "Fatty Bolger", "Bill Ferny"]
   },

   {
      "question" : "What is the name of the Great River that the Fellowship rows down after leaving Lothlorien?",
      "correctAns" : "Anduin",
      "multChoice" : ["Celduin", "Isen", "Bruinen", "Anduin", "Entwash"]
   },

   {
      "question" : "Who cut the One Ring from Sauron's hand during the Battle of the Last Alliance?",
      "correctAns" : "Isildur",
      "multChoice" : ["Elendil", "Arathorn", "Beren", "Isildur", "Elrond"]
   },

   {
      "question" : "Who is Shelob the last child of?",
      "correctAns" : "Ungoliant",
      "multChoice" : ["Melkor", "Yavanna", "Melian", "Nienna", "Ungoliant"]
   },

   {
      "question" : "What is the name of Gandalf's sword?",
      "correctAns" : "Glamdring",
      "multChoice" : ["Anduril", "Orcrist", "Glamdring", "Gurthang", "Herugrim"]
   },

   {
      "question" : "What is the date of Bilbo's and Frodo's birthday?",
      "correctAns" : "September 22nd",
      "multChoice" : ["September 22nd", "October 24th", "August 1st", "April 9", "June 18th"]
   },

   {
      "question" : "At the end of Return of the King, who bore the Three Elvish Rings?",
      "correctAns" : "Elrond, Galadriel, and Gandalf",
      "multChoice" : ["Aragorn, Arwen, and Galadriel", "Bilbo, C&iacuterdan, and Celebrimbor", "Galadriel, Celeborn, and Glorfindel", "Elrond, Galadriel, and Gandalf", "Vilya, Nenya, Narya"]
   },

   {
      "question" : "How old is Frodo when he sets out from the Shire with the Ring?",
      "correctAns" : "50",
      "multChoice" : ["25", "33", "41", "50", "67"]
   },



]